higheredjobs.com 2014-11-26

# Privacy Policy - HigherEdJobs

Internet Employment Linkage has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/ "Privacy Program Requirements") including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personally identifiable information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, www.higheredjobs.com.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. _If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us first:_ contact the Operations Department at [privacy@higheredjobs.com](mailto:privacy@higheredjobs.com) or by postal mail at 715 Lake Street, Suite 400, Oak Park, IL 60301. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

This Privacy Policy governs the collection and use of user data from those portions of the HigherEdJobs.com website that are available to the public without a login ID or password (the "Public Site") and those portions, such as the Employer Section and My HigherEdJobs, that we restrict to users with a login ID and password (the "Restricted Site"). The Public Site and the Restricted Site are, collectively, called the "Web Site." Except where specified otherwise, the provisions in this Privacy Policy apply to the Web Site as a whole.

## PRIVACY PHILOSOPHY

Internet Employment Linkage Inc., publisher of HigherEdJobs.com, has created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to keeping personally identifiable information private. Our data collection policies allow you to choose how much information you provide us and how we use the information you have shared. It is our intent to use this information to help further your success in seeking or filling a position in the field of higher education through the use of our Web Site.

## THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

A. Anonymous Information. You can always browse the Public Site and search for posted positions without providing any personally identifiable information to HigherEdJobs.com. We gather general information about the number of users browsing the Web Site, the number of users who view certain posted positions, and how users navigate through our Web Site. This information is collected anonymously and only in the aggregate. We use this information to provide aggregated statistical feedback to the institutions posting positions on our Web Site, to publicize our Web Site and to further develop our Web Site to maximize the benefits realized by our users.

B. Personally Identifiable Information. HigherEdJobs.com collects personally identifiable information when you register for a personal account through My HigherEdJobs, create a Resume Profile and when you elect to receive information from us through Insider Update or other similar "opt-in" services we may provide. "Opt-in" services are only offered when the user purposefully checks a box or another method of indicating their specific intention of being included for the service so provided. When you create a user ID and password, we collect your name, e-mail address, state and country of residence, academic/administrative focus, years in higher education and years of work experience. We may also request other information such as your zip code, career level, highest degree earned, salary level and professional affiliations. Any information you provide to HigherEdJobs.com when registering for a personal account is maintained and accessible only by HigherEdJobs.com. We use this information in the aggregate for demographic purposes. We may use that information to e-mail you information about maintenance schedules, new institutional subscribers information, as well as special promotions and other general updates from HigherEdJobs.com or third parties that may be relevant to you and your search for a position in higher education. HigherEdJobs.com provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of these types of communications. If you choose to receive these types of communications at the time of registration or by opting in for a particular service, and later decide you no longer want to receive them, simply follow the opt-out procedures contained on the Web Site. WE DO NOT SELL OR OTHERWISE SHARE ANY OF YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION WITH ANY THIRD PARTY OTHER THAN IS OUTLINED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@higheredjobs.com](mailto:privacy@higheredjobs.com).

C. Resume Center. If you register for a personal My HigherEdJobs account, you will have the option of posting a form of your resume on the Restricted Site. We request certain personally identifiable information in order for you to post your resume, such as your name and address, e-mail address and experience working in higher education. We include this information, when and only if you so elect, in a database for institutional and other paying subscribers to search for potential candidates online. In addition, you have the ability to draft a personal resume and cover letter in the resume textbox. There are two primary ways you can use the Resume Center:

  1. You can create and store your resume on our database, but _not_ allow it to be searched by any institutions of higher education or other employer-subscribers. Not allowing your resume to be searchable means that you can use it to apply for a position online, but it will _not_ be searchable through our resume database.
  2. You can store your resume in our database and allow it to be searched by universities and employers that subscribe for access to our resume database. You may elect to have your personal contact information disclosed to universities and employers searching our database, or not have any personal contact information disclosed. You may remove your resume from our searchable database at any time. However, university and other subscribers who have paid for access to the database may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use, or privacy of resumes, nor any information disclosed on your resume or cover letter posted on our Web Site. Please note that once you create a resume online and permit it to be searched, all information contained in your resume and cover letter can be collected and used by our paying subscribers. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties, for which Internet Employment Linkage, Inc. is not responsible.

D. Other Technical Information/Cookies. We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Web Site. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web Site. In addition to information provided by your browser, we use "cookies" for remembering your preferences, maintaining information about whether you are currently logged into our systems, and tracking click streams. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster service, consistent, updated results, and a more personalized site experience. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies. We do not use cookies to store any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. If you use My HigherEdJobs and request us to do so, we will use a cookie to help us recall information about your account such as your user name and password. In the event you refuse cookies, however, you may not be able to take advantage of benefits offered by our Web Site.

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. To learn more about our advertising company's use of clear gifs, please go to [DoubleClick](https://www.google.com/doubleclick/).

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see "Choice and Opt-out."

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers, tracking utilities) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers' or Users' personally identifiable information. [See the "Third Party Advertisers" section.]

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by www.higheredjobs.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. [See the "Third Party Advertisers" section.]

E. Job Postings. Persons, whether as individuals or as employees of a business who use the Employer Section or the Single Posting Pages of the Web Site may be asked for their business email addresses, business address and phone, billing information, and a password. Although there is no cost to Job Seekers for using the services on the Web Site, Job Posters will be charged a fee for requested services. We use data collected from Job Posters to provide requested services.

F. Payments By Credit Card. We use an outside bank merchant account to verify credit card data so we can bill and account for products sold to Job Posters. This company does not retain, share, store or use credit card data for any other purposes.

G. Third Party Advertisers. The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by third party ad servers. We share Web site usage information about users with reputable third parties for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site.

Our third party advertisers use cookies, which allow it to recognize a user's cookie when a user visits this site. The information that our ad server collects and shares through this technology is not personally identifiable.

If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose information about your individual visits to our site, or personally identifiable information that you provide, such as your name, e-mail address, faculty area, or professional associations to any outside parties, except when we believe, in good faith, that such release is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with law, (ii) protect the rights, property or safety of HigherEdJobs.com, our users, or others, or (iii) if HigherEdJobs.com is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

We may also provide your personally identifiable information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us.

## LINKS TO 3RD PARTY SITES

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Internet Employment Linkage. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

## SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS

Our Web site includes Social Media Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## YOU CAN MODIFY YOUR INFORMATION AT ANY TIME

HigherEdJobs.com allows you to change, correct or remove your personally identifiable information from the Web Site at any time. To do so, simply log into your My HigherEdJobs account, go to your account profile, and you will find options for editing the information you have submitted. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

You may also opt-out of any communication by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [jobseeker@higheredjobs.com](mailto:jobseeker@higheredjobs.com). In order to keep information fresh and pertinent, your account on the restricted site (My HigherEdJobs) will be deleted after six (6) months of non-use. In addition, our Web Site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us. Users may change this information any time and as often as necessary. HigherEdJobs.com does reserve the right to send a one-time registration confirmation e-mail, and infrequent service messages to its customers to inform them of specific changes to HigherEdJobs.com's services or special alerts, regardless of email contact opt-in status. Examples of such a special alert message, to the email address you supplied, would be notification of the impending closing of an account that is believed to be abandoned or the addition of important new features to an existing service.

Job Posters may update their account information and manage their job postings by logging into their account through the Post a Job section of our Web site.

## SECURITY MEASURES ARE IN PLACE

This Web Site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information contained on our Web Site. During the subscription or registration process, you will have the option to provide a password for your account. We authenticate your access to our Web Site through your use of your user ID and password, and protect your information with firewall protections. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. Particularly sensitive information, such as a college or university's credit card number collected for a commerce transaction, is encrypted prior to transmission using a Blowfish Encryption Algorithm and purged upon receipt. See [www.schneier.com/blowfish.html](http://www.schneier.com/blowfish.html) for more information on the protections provided by this encryption. Please be advised that you are ultimately responsible for the security of your HigherEdJobs.com user ID and password. Please take care to store your HigherEdJobs.com user ID separately from your account password, or better yet, choose a password that you do not need to write down at all.

## CHILDREN

We do not specifically collect information about children, nor do we authorize use of this Web Site by children.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email prior to the change becoming effective. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personally identifiable information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about HigherEdJobs.com's Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [privacy@higheredjobs.com](mailto:privacy@higheredjobs.com).

THANK YOU FOR USING HIGHEREDJOBS.COM.

Last Updated: 2/19/2014
